BENJAMIN DFI TFNRF WFB DFVFI OPFR

- benjdelt@gmail.com
- line benjdelt.github.io/
- **6** 604-762-5243
- **◊** Vancouver BC
- in benjdelt
- O benjdelt

Skills

LANGUAGES

JavaScript

Python

Ruby

HTML

CSS

TOOLS & LIBRARIES

Node.js

Express

Diango

JQuery

Ruby on Rails

Bootstrap Sass

PostgreSQL

MvSOL

MonaoDB

Git

Education

July 2018 to Oct.

Lighthouse Labs Diploma Web Development

2018

2007

IEPSCF Ath-Flobecq Sept. **Bachelor Accounting** 2004 to Sept.

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with experience in React, Python and Django. I have a passion for building apps and creative problem solving. I bring a strong focus to details and good time management skills from my 6 years of experience in the government finance sector. Fluent in English and French, Legally entitled to work in Canada

Experience

TalentMarketplace

Vancouver, BC Apr. 2019 to Current

Contract Web Developer

TalentMarketplace is an online, project professional recruitment platform.

- Tech stack: Diango, React, Redux, PostgreSOL
- Robustly resolved bugs and implemented features on an existing, enterprise code base to guickly deliver system enhancements that reached thousands of users
- Managed ticket progress through backlog in an Agile sprint development environment
- Integrated new front-end functionalities on a large existing code base
- Thoroughly QAed (white box tested) all code to have a ticket return rate of 0%

Shuup

Vancouver, BC Feb. 2019 to Mar. 2019

Developer Intern Multi Vendor Marketplace Platform and Custom Development Services

Tech Stack: Python, Django, JavaScript, React, MySQL

- Participated in Open Source development to add features and fix issues
- •Developed features taking advantage of Django's application system
- Managed ticket progress through Jira following a 2 week sprint agile environment
- · Wrote user documentation

TalentMarketplace

Vancouver, BC Oct. 2018 to Feb. 2019

Volunteer Web Developer

- TalentMarketplace is an online, project professional recruitment platform. • Tech stack: Django, React, Redux, PostgreSQL
- Utilized **Git source control** through Bitbucket repository to pull, branch, push code and create pull requests
- Managed ticket progress through backlog in an Agile sprint development environment
- Robustly resolved bugs and implemented features on an existing, enterprise code base to quickly deliver system enhancements that reached thousands of users
- Thoroughly QAed (white box tested) all code to have a ticket return rate of 0%

Wallonia-Brussels Federation

Brussels (Belgium) July 2012 to June 2018

The French-speaking Community / Wallonia-Brussels Federation exercises its competencies in the French language region of Belgium and in regard to the institutions that fall under its purview in the bilingual Brussels-Capital Region.

- Effective task prioritization to meet tight deadlines under pressure
- Worked as part of a team of 4 controllers to control subsidies and public contracts for the whole Federation
- Implemented unique procedure for different functional departments to harmonize control operations
- Guided accountants for their budget requirements
- Inspected public contracts and subsidies before charging the budget for a total of 8 billion euros per year

Latest Projects

One Army - Community Platform: Open Source Contributions

Nov. 2019 to Current

Web application for the Precious Plastic community to collaborate around the world and tackle plastic waste, using TypeScript, React, Node and Firebase.

- Investigated bugs in unfamiliar code base and technologies
- Provided and thoroughly tested bug fixes while following contributing guidelines · Communicated efficiently to facilitate code reviews
- Many-Faced God

Aug. 2019 to Oct. 2019

Group project from Lighthouse Labs' Alumni Lab. A full stack web app built with React and Express. Upload a photo, detect all the faces and swap the faces of the people you don't know with AI generated ones.

Apr. 2019 to May 2019

A full stack web app built with React, Redux and Express. It connects to the Spotify API and to API Seeds Lyrics to automatically get the information and the lyrics of the track currently being played on the user's Spotify account.

Mentoring

Canada Learning Code -

Apr. 2019 to

Current

Nov. 2018 to

Current

Canada Learning Code designs, delivers, and partners on technology education for Canadians.

- Ladies Learning Code Data Insights with Python for Beginners
- Ladies Learning Code HTML & CSS for Beginners
- Answered questions and provided additional explanations
- · Taught basic bug solving skills to help students overcome difficulties
- · Offered extra challenges to stronger students
- Consulted with instructors and other mentors regarding common pitfalls encountered by students

Lighhouse Labs ·

Web Development bootcamp that offers part-time and full-time programs. Mentored as a volunteer during workshops for beginners

- HTML & CSS Essentials
- Pvthon Essentials
- · Answered questions and provided additional explanations
- Taught basic bug solving skills to help students overcome difficulties
- · Offered extra challenges to stronger students
- Consulted with instructors and other mentors regarding common pitfalls encountered by students